Hyatt-Mayor Genealogical Collection
Hyatt-Mayor Genealogical Collection
Undated
Hyatt family.; Mayor family.
5.0 linear ft.
Correspondence, incoming and outgoing; certificates; contracts; family trees; notebooks; notes, books; magazines; and pamphlets. Material pulled from the papers of various members of the Hyatt and Mayor families, especially those of Audella Hyatt and Harriet Hyatt Mayor.
2604726
Biographical History
For Biographical History of the Hyatt and Mayor families see the finding aids of individual family members.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Hyatt-Mayor Genealogical Collection includes correspondence, certificates of birth, marriage, and baptism, contracts, family trees, notebooks and notes, and published material consisting of books on family genealogy, magazines, and pamphlets. The Genealogical materials have been pulled from the papers of various members of the Hyatt and Mayor families, especially those of Audella Hyatt (Mrs. Alpheus Hyatt II) and Harriet Hyatt Mayor. Whenever possible the original source of the materials has been noted on each folder. Also included are unidentified papers from the Hyatt-Mayor family papers consisting of correspondence, subject file, manuscripts, and published material. They have been divided into parts but have been left unarranged within their respective group.
Correspondence includes incoming and outgoing correspondence, correspondence to and from others, and correspondence arranged by subject. Incoming and outgoing correspondence consists of letters to and from various family members of the Hyatt and Mayor families. Correspondence by subject consists of a letter-file and a large folder entitled "Letters Giving the History of the Mayor Family." Subject File includes certificates of birth, baptism, and marriage, chancery proceedings, contracts, DAR applications, family trees, notebooks, notes and wills. Published Material contains books, magazines, and pamphlets on genealogy. Unidentified papers from the Hyatt-Mayor family papers consist of correspondence, artifacts, a map, photographs, and negatives, a photobook, postcards, manuscript materials and published materials.
Arrangement of the Collection
Incoming letters are arranged alphabetically by author and outgoing correspondence is arranged chronologically. Correspondence to and from others is arranged alphabetically by author. The original order of the correspondence has been maintained for both groups, with the exception of a few items removed from the letter-file. Items removed from the letter-file are arranged alphabetically by author following the letter-file. Subject File is arrange alphabetically by type. Published Material is also arranged alphabetically by type, but is then organized alphabetically by title. Unidentified papers are divided into parts but have been unarranged within their respective group.
Related Material
The has numerous collections for the Hyatt-Mayor families. For information on members of the Hyatt, Mayor, Beebe, and Huntington families see for the finding aids of individual family members.
Subject and Genre Headings
Hyatt, Audella Beebe, 1840-1932.; Mayor, Harriet H. (Harriet Hyatt), 1868-1960.; Mayor, Alfred Goldsborough, 1868-1922.; Mayor family.; Hyatt family.; Genealogy.; Correspondence.; Genealogies (histories); Birth certificates.; Marriage certificates.; Contracts.; Notebooks.; Notes (documents); Books.; Magazines (periodicals); Pamphlets.; Maps (documents); Photographs.; Negatives (photographs); Postcards.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - Incoming Correspondence (Box 1)
  - Outgoing Correspondence, 1913; 1914 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence To and From Others (Box 1)
  - Correspondence by Subject
    - Following letters transferred from the Audella Beebe Hyatt Collection
      - Incoming Correspondence
        - A - D (Box 1)
        - F (Box 1)
        - Hyatts (various) (Box 1)
        - Hyatts (various) (Box 2)
        - H, J - M (Box 2)
        - O (Box 2)
          For further correspondence of Lizzie A. Hyatt Ogden on genealogy See Audella Beebe Hyatt Collection, Correspondence by Subject, Notebook
        - S, T, W (Box 2)
        - Unidentified (Box 2)
      - Outgoing Correspondence
        - 1889-1890 (Box 2)
      - Correspondence To and From Others (Box 2)
    - "Letters Giving the History of the Mayor Family" (transferred from the Alfred Goldsborough Mayor) (Box 2)
- Subject File
  - Certificates - Birth, Baptism (Box 3)
  - Certificates - Marriage (Box 3)
  - Chancery Proceedings (Box 3)
  - Contracts, 3 folders (Box 3)
  - D.A.R. applications (Box 3)
  - Family Trees (Box 3)
  - "Indexed Genealogical Register" (Box 3)
  - Notebook, 2 (Box 4)
  - Notes (transferred from the Audella Beebe Hyatt Collection), 3 folders (Box 4)
  - Notes (transferred from the Harriet Randolph Hyatt Mayor Collection), 5 folders (Box 5)
  - Notes, 3 folders (Box 5)
  - Wills - William Hyatt, 1910 (Box 5)
- Published Material
  - Books:
    - Beebe Genealogy (Box 6)
    - Beebe Genealogy (Box 6)
    - Direct Line from Robert and Mary Reynolds (Box 6)
    - Mayer Family (Box 7)
    - Reynolds Family 1530-1959 (Box 7)
    - Robert and Mary Reynolds of Boston and the Hyatt Family (Box 7)
    - Welsh-Hyatt and Kindred (Box 8)
  - Magazines:
    - Early Settlers of New York (Box 8)
    - The Magazine of American Genealogy (Box 8)
    - New England Historical and Genealogical Register (Box 8)
  - Pamphlets:
    - The Edson Story (transferred from the Anna Hyatt Huntington Collection) (Box 9)
    - A - I (transferred from the Harriet Randolph Hyatt Mayor Collection) (Box 9)
    - R - S (Box 9)
    - Goldsborough (Box 9)
    - Mayer Family (Box 9)
    - Scottish Record Society - The Burgesses and Guild Brethren of Glasgow (Box 9)
    - Scottish Record Society - Calendar of Writs (Box 9)
    - Scottish Record Society - Inventory of Pitfirrane Writs (Box 9)
    - Scottish Record Society - Protocol Book (Box 9)
    - Scottish Record Society - Roll of Edinburgh Burgesses (Box 9)
- Unidentified Papers from the Hyatt-Mayor Family Papers
  - Correspondence (Box 10)
  - Subject File
    - Artifacts (Box 10)
    - Map, Baltimore City, 1864 (Box 10)
    - Photographs and Negatives (Box 10)
    - Photographs and Negatives - Photobook (Box 10)
    - Postcards (Box 10)
  - Manuscripts (Box 10)
  - Published Material
    - Book - Der Schulmeister von Tannenrode (Box 10)